<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="recipe_details">
        <item>Step 1 Pressure cook carrots, peas and corn
To make the burger patty, pressure cook the carrot, peas and sweet corn for 1 whistle or until soft.
\n\n
Step 2 Add the spices
Add the cooked vegetables, chopped onions, red chilli powder, lemon juice, garam masala powder, salt and ginger-garlic paste to a large bowl.
\n\n
Step 3 Add mashed potatoes
Add lemon juice and mashed potatoes in the bowl, mix well until evenly combined. Shape the mixture into small/medium patties.
\n\n
Step 4 Shallow fry the patties
Now heat oil in a pan over medium flame. Roll the prepared patties in the breadcrumbs and shallow fry until golden brown on both sides.
\n\n
Step 5 Keep aside
Remove and keep aside.
\n\n
Step 6 Prepare the burger
Take one half of the burger bun. Spread some butter and place the lettuce on top.
\n\n
Step 7 Add slices onions, cucumber and tomatoes
Place the prepared vegetable patty on top. Top up with slices of onion, tomato, cucumber and cheese. If you want to make it even more delicious and healthy replace cheese with eggless mayonnaise.
\n\n
Step 8 Burger is ready
Cover it with the other half of the burger bun. If desired, add some ketchup on top. Secure it with a toothpick if desired.
\n\n
Step 9 Serve!
Serve at once with french fries. Make sure you like this recipe, rate it and let us know in the comments how it turned out to be.\n</item>
        <item>
            Step 1 Preheat the oven at 250 degree Celsius : \n
To prepare this delicious Cheese Pizza recipe, preheat the oven on convection mode at 250 degree Celsius. Meanwhile, spread the tomato sauce evenly on each pizza base. Take a chopping board and chop onions, tomatoes, capsicum and mushroom on it.
            \n\n
            Step 2 Microwave the veggies for about a minute : \n
Mix all the chopped vegetables and seasoning in a bowl. Microwave these vegetables in a microwave-safe bowl for around 30-40 seconds or a minute. Spread this vegetable topping on each pizza base. Sprinkle grated mozzarella cheese at the top of each pizza.

tom
            \n\n
Step 3 Bake the pizza at for 10-12 minutes : \n
You can either bake this pizza in a microwave or you can use a non-stick tawa for the same. However, in this recipe we have used microwave. Bake the pizza on the high rack at 250 degree Celsius till the cheese melts. It will take around 10-12 minutes. Cut the delicious Cheese Pizza into slices and serve with sauces.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Step 1
To prepare this delicious recipe, boil 6 cups of water and add a little salt and olive oil in it. Boil the noodles with salt and few drops of olive oil in boiling water for 15-20 minutes. Now drain the water and rinse with cool water and add a little extra oil.
\n\n
Step 2
Heat chili oil in a pan over medium flame and add the chopped onions along with the red bell peppers and capsicum. stir fry for 3-4 minutes with a pinch of salt.
\n\n
Step 3
Add soy sauce, black pepper powder, ajinomoto and vinegar and stir well. Saute for 2 minutes more. Add the boiled noodles and stir for 5 minutes and serve with tomato sauce and green chilli sauce according to your taste.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Step 1 Chop the potatoes : \n
To prepare this easy recipe, you need to make sure that they are cut in the right shape and size. They should neither be too thick, nor too thin and should be cut clean and sharp. The trick is to first slice the potatoes and then cut them lengthwise. You can also use a fries cutter for that long, even shape.
\n\n
Step 2 Soak cut potatoes in ice-cold water for 10-15 minutes : \n
Now, wash the potatoes under running water till they are squeaky clean. Place them in a bowl of iced water for 10 to 15 minutes. Keep them submerged in water or they will turn black.
\n\n
Step 3 Deep fry the potato fries : \n
Now, heat the oil in a deep bottomed pan. Once the smoke starts appearing, reduce the flame and allow it to acquire a lower temperature. Now, deep fry the potatoes in batches. Keep the flame low. This will make them crunchy and also help retain their colour.
\n\n
Step 4 Sprinkle salt and pepper and serve hot : \n
Drain excess oil and place them on an absorbent paper. Allow them to cool. Now sprinkle salt and pepper and toss well. Serve immediately with ketchup. They can also be served with burgers and cutlets.\n
        </item>

        <item>Step 1 Prepare the vegetable stuffing : \n
To prepare this exotic delight, first prepare the vegetable filling. To do so finely chop onion, garlic, ginger, mushroom, tofu, cabbage and cilantro. Once done mix all these vegetables in a bowl. Add soy sauce in the bowl and toss the vegetables to combine them well. Keep aside for further use.
\n\n
Step 2 Prepare the dough : \n
Next, prepare the dough for covering the momos. In a bowl add all purpose flour and water. Mix together to form a smooth dough. Cover the dough and keep aside.
\n\n
Step 3 Roll out the dough and obtain several tiny circles : \n
Now, roll out the dough using a rolling pin (similar to a chapati preparation). Roll into a thin sheet of dough, but not too thin. Out of this cut out small circles.
\n\n
Step 4 Stuff in the filling in the momos : \n
Next, fill the centre of each of these circles with vegetable filling prepared in step 1. Once done, start making small folds on the inside using your thumb and forefinger. Lift the sides of the circles and seal them together using a little water. Make sure the momos are properly sealed.
\n\n
Step 5 Steam the momos and serve : \n
Finally, boil water in a steamer. Once the water boils, add momos in the steamer. Leave them undisturbed for 15-20 minutes. Take out and serve ht with dip or chutney of your choice.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Step 1
To prepare this delicious recipe, wash and soak the basmati rice for 20 minutes. Then wash the mushroom to remove all the dirt from it.
\n\n
Step 2
Place a pressure cooker over medium flame and add ghee in it. Once it is heated add bay leaf, cinnamon, cloves, coarse cardamom and fennel seeds. Fry for 2 minutes. Then add chopped onions and saute until it becomes translucent.
\n\n
Step 3
Now, add ginger garlic paste, green chilies, tomato, mushrooms. Mix them well and saute for about 2 minutes. Then add yogurt, red chilli powder, turmeric powder, black pepper powder. Fry them and cook for 2 minutes.
\n\n
Step 4
Next, add soaked basmati rice along with the 4 cups of water in the mixture. Mix them altogether. Close the pressure cooker and cook for 2 whistles.
\n\n
Step 5
Once it is cooked turn off the flame and allow the pressure to be reduced completely. Remove the lid and your Mushroom Biryani is ready to be served. Enjoy!\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Step 1
To prepare this delicious recipe, boil the potatoes for about half and hour in water. Once boiled in the cooker, turn off the flame and carefully start peeling off the skin. Once peeled, mash the potatoes finely.
\n\n
Step 2
Then, add salt, turmeric powder, cumin powder, garam masala, chilli powder and green chillies into the mashed potatoes. Mix well all the ingredients and the potato paste is now ready!
\n\n
Step 3
Next, take the bread slices and spread the potato paste into it. You can spread butter as well on the slices as per your taste.
\n\n
Step 4
Finally, heat a tawa and grease well by drizzling a little bit of butter or oil into it. Carefully place the topped over bread slice on the tawa. Make sure to place the potato paste side on the top and not on the surface of the tawa.
\n\n
Step 5
Once cooked, serve ​potato sandwich​ warm with love. Enjoy your meal!\n
        </item>

        <item>
Step 1 Boil, peel and chop the eggs : \n
To prepare this easy recipe, take a deep-bottomed pan and add enough water to it along with eggs. Let the eggs boil for 10 minutes. After the eggs boil, drain water and let the eggs cool a little before you start peeling and chopping the eggs.
\n\n
Step 2 Add the seasoning and sources to the chopped eggs : \n
Take a bowl and add egg, mayonnaise, salt, mustard paste to the bowl and mix thoroughly. Stir in pepper to the mixture.
\n\n
Step 3 Spread the egg mixture on toasted bread and cover with another slice : \n
Toast the bread slices. Then, take a bread slice, spread butter on it and add the egg mixture on the bread. Cover it up with the other bread slices. Serve!\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Step 1 Boil the pasta : \n
Take a deep bottomed pan and add water to it. Keep it on high flame and add 1 tbsp salt and 2 tbsps of oil in it. Once it comes to a boil, add the pasta it and stir properly. Let it boil and keep stirring to prevent the pasta from sticking the bottom.

macaroni
            \n\n
Step 2 Chop the vegetables : \n
Side-by-side chop all the vegetables. Finely chop the ginger and garlic and keep them aside.

vegetable pasta
            \n\n
Step 3 Saute the veggies for 5-7 minutes : \n
Add some oil in a pan and once it heats up, add the ginger and garlic and stir, let them cook until they turn golden. Add the onions and chillies and stir. When the onions turn translucent, add the tomatoes along with salt.

vegetable pasta
            \n\n
Step 4 Mix in the sauces, mix and add the boiled pasta : \n
Once the tomatoes turn soft, add the capsicums and carrot and mix well. Now, add in the sauces and red chilli powder. Cover and let it cook for 3 minutes and then add the pasta.

vegetable pasta
            \n\n
Step 5 Garnish with oregano and chilli flakes and serve! : \n
Now add the oregano, chilli flakes and Garam masala and give it a good mix without breaking the pasta. You vegetable pasta is ready to be served!

vegetable pasta
            \n\n
Step 6 Easy tips to keep in mind : \n
1. Adding the salt as and when you add the tomatoes helps in cooking the tomatoes faster and makes the whole process quicker.\n2. You can leave out the hot sauce if you prefer less spice and if you are making it for kids. \n3. You can add grated cheese to make it more interesting. But if you are looking for a low-calorie version, this recipe would be the best choice for you.\n4. Adding more vegetables to the recipe will increase the health quotient of the dish.\n5. Remember to add oil to the boiled pasta after straining it. This will prevent it from sticking together and your final product will come out beautiful and fresh looking. \n6. You can garnish it with coriander leaves or freshly chopped chives, a little green always lights up food!\n
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>